Guide to the Douglass L. Alligood Papers, 1963-2013
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Douglass L. Alligood papers 1963-2013
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Alligood, Douglass L.
1.0 Linear Feet 100 Items
Advertising executive with BBDO and Uniworld agencies, and RCA. One of the first African Americans to become an executive in the advertising industry in the United States
Collection spans the years 1963-2013, with the bulk of materials spanning 1980-2006. It contains primarily of research reports focused on ethnic minority (African American, Asian, Hispanic) and youth consumer market demographics and media issues such as television viewing habits. The collection also includes clippings and a 1963 audio recording, Adventures in Negro History. Companies referenced in the materials include BBDO, RCA, Chrysler and Pepsi. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Douglass L. Alligood Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2013.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1956 Bachelor of Fine Arts, Bradley University.
1957-1960 Service, United States Air Force.
1962-1971 Media Planner, Marketing Group Supervisor, Account Executive, BBDO.
1971-1983 Director of Corporate Advertising, Radio Corporation of America.
1983 President, Uniworld.
1984-2013 Senior Vice-President for Horizontal/Special Markets, BBDO
1994 Centurion Society, Bradley University
2005 Publication of Color Television, co-authored with Cristina Pieraccini
2010 ADCOLOR Lifetime Achievement Award
2011 BBDO and Bradley co-sponsor the Douglass L. Alligood Award, to fund capstone student projects that promote diversity in business.
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1963-2013, with the bulk of materials spanning 1980-2006. It contains primarily of research reports focused on ethnic minority (African American, Asian, Hispanic) and youth consumer market demographics and media issues such as television viewing habits. The collection also includes clippings and a 1963 phonograph record, Adventures in Negro History. Companies referenced in the materials include BBDO, RCA, Chrysler and Pepsi.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Alligood, Douglass L.
Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn, Inc
Chrysler Corporation
Pepsi-Cola Company
Radio Corporation of America
Advertising
Advertising -- History
Advertising -- History -- United States
Advertising agencies
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Advertising and youth
Advertising executives
Advertising executives -- United States
African American consumers
African American television viewers
Asian American consumers
Demographic surveys
Demographic surveys -- United States
Hispanic American consumers
Hispanic American television viewers
Marketing research
Marketing research -- United States
Minority television viewers -- United States
Television advertising
Television advertising -- United States
Television -- Social aspects -- United States
Television viewers -- United States
Young consumers
Phonograph records
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Alvin Achenbaum Papers
Jim Brown Papers
Joy Golden Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company Chicago Office Media Resources and Research Department Records
J. Walter Thompson Company Detroit Office Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports
J. Walter Thompson Company New York Office Research Department Records
Detailed Description of Collection
- Printed Materials, 1963-2013
  - Aging Americans, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Analysis of Black Audience Primetime Network Viewing Preferences, 1985, 1987, (2 folders)
  - Asian Population of New York, 2002
  - Asian Populations in the U.S. Today, 2003
  - BBDO Diversity Inc./Minority Advertising: A Plan for Profit, 1998
  - BBDO Media Update (newsletter), 1988-1989
  - BBDO Special Markets Opportunities
    - Vol. 4 no. 2 Targeting Diversity, 1999
    - Vol. 4 no. 3 Urban Inspiration, 1999
    - Vol. 4 no. 4 Urban Highways, 1999
    - Vol. 4 no. 5 New for Year 2000, 1999
    - Vol. 4 no. 6 Reaching Ethnic Markets, 2000
    - Vol. 4 no. 7 Urban Matrix, 2000
  - BBDO Special Markets Update, 1991
  - Black Consumer Market: RCA Consumer Electronics Discussion Paper, 1979
  - Black Consumer Market Facts, 1993
  - Black Television Viewing, 1996
  - Black TV Viewing Choices, 2007
  - Black TV Viewing Preferences, 2003
  - Black Viewer Preferences, 2006
  - Black Viewers Broaden Their Choices, 1999
  - Black Viewers Sharpen Their Focus, 2000
  - Black Viewing of Primetime Television, 1989-1990
  - Black Viewing Preferences, 2002
  - Clippings, 1966-1969
  - CV/Biographical sketch, 2013 (Box 2)
  - Editorial + Audience Selected Minority Publications, 2001-2002, (2 folders)
  - Hispanic Consumer Market Facts, 1993
  - Hispanic Dimensions II, 2004
  - Hispanic Readers of Consumer Publications, 1990
  - Hispanic Readers of General Audience Consumer Publications, 1989
  - Hispanics and Network Television, 2003
  - Negro Media Analysis for Chrysler Motors Corporation, 1963
  - Pepsi-Cola Co. Education Marketing Sessions II, 1985
  - Special Markets: What Makes Them Special?, 1996, (2 folders)
  - Top 20 Black and Hispanic DMA Market Rank and Demographic Rank, 2003
  - Youth in the City, 2006
- Audiovisual Materials, 1963
  - Adventures in Negro History. Produced by Highlight Radio Productions, Detroit, Mich. HRP-101; sponsored by Pepsi-Cola Co. 12" Record album. Two copies with different cover art. 1963 (Box 3)